Chairul Akmal

Web Developer/Marine Biologist



Contact

Email:

chairulakmal@live.com

Address:

Kebayoran Baru, Jakarta







Languages

English - IELTS 8 Iapanese - Fair

Hobbies

- Books
- Podcasts
- Open Source Projects

Personal Profile

Full Stack Web Developer with recent experience building web app utilizing Node, Express, Vue, React, Postgres, GraphQL, etc. Marine Biologist with field and desk research experience skilled in Scientific Scuba Diving and Statistical Analysis with R Studio. Comfortable working in a team or as an individual with experience working in and leading international teams.

Education

Hacktiv8, Indonesia 2020 JavaScript Full Stack Development

James Cook University, Australia 2018 - 2019 Master of Science: Marine Biology

Tohoku University, Japan **2012 - 2016** Bachelor's Degree: **Marine Biology**

Experience

Translation Volunteer - 01/2020 to present **ethereum.org/id**, Zug

- Translated more than 80% of ethereum.org website from English into Bahasa Indonesia
- Coordinate with ethereum.org website team on translation priorities
- Proposed creation of a glossary for common terms to unify translations across languages and projects

Translation Volunteer - 02/2020 **chairulakmal.com/trust/**

 Translated open source JavaScript web game into Bahasa Indonesia with successful PR into the original repository of creator <u>@ncase</u>

Researcher – 01/2019 to 12/2019 **James Cook University**, Townsville

 Completed meta-analytical research based on Global Coral Reef Restoration Database, looking into the effectiveness of coral nurseries in reef restoration

President - 07/2018 to 06/2019

JCU Indonesia Student Association, Townsville

 Organized and lead involvement in student festivals and city-level cultural events such as Townsville Cultural Festival and Cairns Indonesian Festival Vue | React | Redux | React Native | GraphQL | jQuery Node | Express | Postgres | Sequelize | Mongo | Redis R | Python | ArcGIS | Google Earth Engine Jest | Supertest | Git

Portfolios

eth.or.id - Official Website of Ethereum Indonesia

React | Grommet | Node | Netlify

• Official landing page site for Yayasan Ethereum Blockchain Indonesia

Kuinstor - eCommerce Web App

Vue | Express | Postgres | Sequelize | Node | Heroku | Firebase | Magic

- Fashion Commerce website with passwordless login
- Integrated with CMS site at <u>kuinadmin.web.app</u>
 - o test user { email: admin@queen.bee; password: 12345678 }

Entertainme - Movie and Series Catalogue

Mongo | Express | React | Apollo Client | Node | Apollo Server | AWS EC2 & S3

Entertainment website where users can check out current movies or series

Gamvangan - Kanban Board Web App

Vue | Express | Postgres | Sequelize | Node | Heroku | Firebase

Kanban Board web app where teams or individual can organize their tasks

Tataplangit - Astronomy Photo Web App

React | Redux | Express | Heroku | Firebase

App where users can see & search current astronomy photos curated by NASA

Saguku - Sudoku Puzzle Mobile App

React Native | Redux | Expo

Sudoku Puzzle React Native Mobile App built with expo

Training & Workshops

- Data Science Methodology Course by IBM 2020
- Python for Data Science and AI by IBM 2020